

+254728460117 bnamwene@gmail.com

# Namwene Mukabwa

Lead TV Commercial Producer

I have over seven years' experience in multi-media production – news, digital media, TV programmes & commercial productions. I am currently the lead creative for commercial production at Standard Group Limited where I lead the creative team to create, shoot, edit and package content for four TV stations (KTN, KTN NEWS, KTN Burudani and Farmers' TV). I am a team player, resilient, versatile and I easily adapt to change while keeping afloat with new technologies. With great training, skills and relevant experience in TV production, I thrive at bringing on board freshness to anything I touch.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

August 2016 - Present

#### Lead TV Commercial Producer | STANDARD GROUP PLC

I oversee all TV commercial productions for four TV stations (KTN, KTN NEWS, FARMERS TV, and KTN BURUDANI); managing a team of ten creatives serving over fifty business executives. I am charged with working on client briefs to output compelling TV commercials and pitches for the business (Standard Group). I have steadily helped grow the business where we have leapfrogged in quantity and quality of internal commercial productions as well as establishing a loyal client base. I have also ensured that adverts meet the highest standards while satisfying customers.

June 2014 - August 2016

#### TV Producer - KTN/KTN NEWS | STANDARD GROUP PLC

I produced and directed news, programmes and promotions for KTN, KTN NEWS including their digital platforms. My roles included coordinating teams in creating visual content (conceptualizing, scripting, filming, editing), budgeting, directing, digital promotions of shows, managing clients – both internal and external, supervising teams/crew for assigned projects.

Key Achievements

I produced and directed a number of shows from news to entertainment to sports, key among them being Zilizala Viwanjani (a daily live sports magazine show) which I helped develop as well as grow to reaching up to a million views every day (Geopoll). My responsibilities included setting up rundowns, managing the team working on the show, monitoring live show content, travelling to cover sports events, booking guests and participating in editorial content idea generation.

Assistant Producer – KTN (STANDARD GROUP LIMITED) June 2013 – June 2014

I assisted producers and directors and quickly adapted. I directed my first news bulletin within three months and was producing news and my own show within six months.

June 2013 - June 2014

#### Assistant Producer - KTN | (STANDARD GROUP LIMITED)

I assisted producers and directors and quickly adapted. I directed my first news bulletin within three months and was producing news and my own show within six months.

#### **EDUCATION**

2016 - 2016

#### **Long-Form TV Production**

The Aga Khan University - Graduate School of Journalism and

I trained on long form (features and documentaries) story telling techniques in areas idea conceptualization, angling of stories, selecting subjects, shoot/camera techniques, scripting, editing.

2014 - 2014

#### **TV Production**

DW Akademie

I trained in news making with courses including editorial research, scripting, news directing, field shoots, commercial production (adverts), planning and budgeting.

2013 - 2013

### **Radio and TV Production**

Media Development in Africa (MEDEVA)

I trained at the late renowned British film/documentary maker Polly Renton's founded Media Training School. Courses included feature-making, budgeting, creative scripting, TV/Film and Radio production, sound recording, news, adverts, among others.

2008 - 2012

# **Bachelor of Science in Communication and Public Relations**

Communication and Public Relations Moi University

I did communication, public relations and journalism courses.

#### SKILLS

- Budgeting, financial planning
- · Concepting and ideation
- Film and video directing
- · High work ethic
- · Leadership skills
- Multimedia
- Planning
- · Problem solving
- Sign language interpreting
- Storytelling
- Team leadership
- Teamwork
- Time management

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English
- Swahili
- French